<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
		<description>A daily newspaper from turn-of-the-century Egypt, in marked up full text.</description>
		<link>/</link>
		<atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Fire in the Night</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Hernandez-A-Strange-Fascination/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Often in the Egyptian Gazette fire is mentioned as having caused the death of a resident or the destruction of significant property. On January 4th, 1907 for example, the Gazette reports a large fire on a gunwharf that caused thousands of pounds of goods to be destroyed, officially estimated at a current value of 250,000 British pounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another instance of the debilitating effects of fire mentioned in the Gazette was on January 10, 1905. This fire broke out on Tousson Street in Alexandria, at a store filled with chandeliers, lamps, and large amounts of petroleum. Although a fire engine was on scene 5 minutes after the alarm was activated, eight hoses continuously dumping water could not stop the fire for two hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These announcements had vital potential impact on the citizens of Alexandria to raise awareness of the absolute devastation fire could cause and the necessity for precautions against such a danger. The Gazette’s report of fire damage from around the world served the purpose of bringing a more thorough knowledge of the universal issue of uncontrolled fires to the people of Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the fire fighting techniques of the day were not entirely effective, as realized in the above example, the explicit, long term, and life threatening effects of fire were a necessary understanding among the people of Alexandria in those years, and the Gazette provided consistent documentation to serve that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Hernandez-A-Strange-Fascination/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Can women be happy without men?</title>
				<link>/curiosities/sonali-pustam-blog/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I found this article on women and marriage while finding articles for my analysis project. My project was on wedding fashion, and this article talks about how women don’t consider marrying a man the ultimate way to get a happy life anymore. The writer of this article is very angry about it, saying “Where else [women’s papers] would anyone dare to imply that woman was sufficiently idiotic to believe that marriage “of itself alone” guaranteed anything?” I honestly kind of thought this article was funny. It was just funny to see the writer get so worked up they had to write an article about it that is mostly made up of quotes and not a lot of their own thoughts (pretty bad journalism if you ask me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something interesting about this was the fact that women are being blamed for the decline in marriage within this article, when there are incidents like one I found in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&quot;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;- a crazy man killing his wife. Similar to in the Gazette, the writer of the blog post suggests the woman may be at fault for her unhappy marriage. They suggest that she might have cheated on her husband, causing him to kill her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, there is another blog post, titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Doring-blogpost/&quot;&gt;“Women Are Always Lying?”&lt;/a&gt;, which describes an article that rants about how women lie to men by changing their appearance (presumably through makeup). Women are depicted as “a creature of broad and gradual curves, whose first duty it is to persuade you that she is the shape of the fashionable corset…” I can’t speak for women back then, but now women really don’t dress up for the sake of impressing men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When women are treated like this by men in newspaper articles, its really no wonder why they create their own newspapers to say that “it is possible to be as happy without a man’s love as with it.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/sonali-pustam-blog/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Mistreatment or misunderstanding?</title>
				<link>/curiosities/amyleebrown-blog/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Upon visiting the mosque at the University of al Azhar, Mr. Sheldon Amos, judge of the Native Court, claims that he was met with “considerable rudeness” on behalf of the students there. This incident caused the chancellor of the university to face repercussions from the government, being required to implement a new system for visitors at the institution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parts of Mr. Amos’ story do not add up. He claims that the students were rude to him, but at the time he visited the mosque, there was a commotion among the students due to a sudden rain shower. The chancellor of the school claims the visitors were probably sent in the direction of disorder, and that any claims of rudeness are simply a misunderstanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writer of this June 13, 1906 article in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; seems to believe Mr. Amos. They claim that his job as judge of the Native Court means that he has thorough knowledge of Arabic and could not possibly mistake jostling for rudeness. They even go so far as to question if the chancellor of the school was there at the time of the incident. The writer of the article seems to have some preconceived notions about this university. They claim that an Indian student was recently made fun of for his political views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to outside sources, Amos was born in 1872 in London. His full name was Percy Maurice Maclardie Sheldon Amos. He was appointed to the Cairo Native Court in 1903. He was educated at Cambridge and came from a very wealthy and well-known family. When considering the reasons for the unrest in the article, it is worth noting that Amos was a European man with a position of power in Egypt. European presence in Egypt was agitating to many Egyptians, and as a result caused unrest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article is not in any particular section of the paper, but is its own section. The writers of the article input their own opinions on the topic, which is something I have seen in many other articles in the newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources:
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.laits.utexas.edu/cairo/history/modern/modern.html&quot;&gt;https://www.laits.utexas.edu/cairo/history/modern/modern.html&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vqronline.org/essay/mixed-courts-egypt&quot;&gt;https://www.vqronline.org/essay/mixed-courts-egypt&lt;/a&gt;
- &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/10.1093/ref:odnb/9780198614128.001.0001/odnb-9780198614128-e-30403;jsessionid=848062D8750262DB8B32285B5E341BE5&quot;&gt;Dictionary of National Biography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/amyleebrown-blog/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Marriage &amp; Divorce</title>
				<link>/curiosities/jarmon-blog/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For my blog post, I chose to talk about the topic of Marriage &amp;amp; Divorce in the year of 1907, around the month August. I was particularly intrigued by the emphasis on marriage being placed in the Egyptian Gazette newspaper which is opposed to what we see in these modern times. One specific section in my reading that gathered my interest was titled “Alexandria Merchant Divorce” published on August 6, 1907.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief overview about the story resulted in the end of a marriage between Mr. William Getty, a cotton merchant of Alexandria and his wife. Over the past years, she strayed away and disappeared from him, leaving him to wonder about her whereabouts and how she was doing. While on her death bed, she had an incurable diseases that she couldn’t be healed from. She wrote a letter to her husband confessing that she was unfaithful to him throughout the duration of their marriage. In defense of her statement, she felt that the money she had leftover should be given to him since she recently became a Christian Scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This excerpt from the passage was quite interesting for me to read because I was fascinated with the explicit details provided and how it was shared with all of the world to see. Although they didn’t share a response from her husband after he received the message from her, I would have wondered what his thoughts, response or even last words to her would have been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reference to this article, I found another interesting topic from the “Egyptian Gazette” in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&quot;&gt;another blog post&lt;/a&gt; about a crazy man killing his wife with an unusual weapon. Although there is no reason for his crazy acts, he committed the crime from speculations that his wife was cheating on him. The magnitude of this article was extremely huge enough to reach the newspaper because people thought the city should be aware of this person and who he is. This article correlated to mine because there was suspicion of cheating in both marriages where the results ended up tragic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/jarmon-blog/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Musical Theater</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Hutson-blog/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The musical theater correspondent surprised me with their knowledge of “Los Huguenots”. The editor well-articulated their points of the show, being critical but also giving a lot of praise. They begin with the overall thoughts, saying it began slowly, but within a little bit of time it picked up into a great show. The following paragraphs go deeper into the different performers and even the chorus. The editor praised all the performers on how well they sang, but nothing really on acting skill. They did go onto write the chorus was a failure of the performance, but did no effect the overall show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really felt as if I went to this show, hearing and visualizing the actors throughout. It was very surprising to me to see such good talent being exhibited during this time period, but also the critic who wrote the excerpt was impressive. I did not know that Egypt had such a well-rounded society with a variety of quality entertainment options. However, I do not think it is anywhere as good as what we are seeing during the present day. Today’s entertainment is a wide variety of genres, which means actors must have a wide variety of skills. One of the analysis projects titled, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/analysis/2016/ragland-analysis&quot;&gt;“The Exploration of Musicians in Alexandria”&lt;/a&gt; agrees with this as well. Ragland, the editor writes that most of the performers were amateurs, but were still greatly supported by the community. He goes on to say that there are no negative reviews that he can find, and the “Los Huguenots” review is no different. The editor does nothing but praise the performance. One last thing I found interesting in his analysis was he said the amount of musicians in the Egyptian Gazette was outstanding. He does not give them by specific name, but mentions the sheer number that are mentioned. I related this to my article because the editor brings up several performers, probably all of the performers from that show.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Hutson-blog/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Nature&#39;s Skin Food</title>
				<link>/organic%20medicines/CastroLeyna-NaturesSkinFood/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;On my Tuesday issue, I found an interesting home remedy for acne and other skin problems. It appears this is something distinct and special to Alexandria. As I was adding the advertisement for page 2 of the October 1906 issue. As a person that loves to learn about skin care and is addicted to by skin care products, this advertisement stood out to me. According to the advertisement, the cream derives from Icilma Natural Water, but most have named it Nature’s Skin Food. From the Icilma Natural water a cream is produced called the Icilma Flour Cream. It is described as the being a no grease or oil cream which I find amazing because most skin care products are filled with oil that, as a result, often causes the skin to produce more oil. This is especially helpful to people that have oily skin which leads them to have problematic skin. The advertisement states that it cleanses the pores of the skin and make it pearly white. I think the Icilma Flour Cream could possibly have been the modern invention of acne remedies in Alexandria during the 1900s. The Icilma Flour Cream sounds like the Neutrogena or Proactive most people preferred to use for their skin problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/ddg.12947&quot;&gt;Back to the Roots: Dermatology in Ancient Egyptian Medicine&lt;/a&gt; in the 2016 Journal of the German Society of Dermatology, Egyptian medicine and the treatment of acute and chronic wounds and injuries such as cosmetic procedures took an important role. Additionally, it seems that another student, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/nunez-blogpost/&quot;&gt;Sabrina Nunez&lt;/a&gt;, also took a curious look into the Iclimia medicine and discovered that Stephen Armitage founded Iclima in 1989. Yet, it seems that herbal medicine was the best option remedy for the Egyptians seeming as the technology was not very advanced, according to the 2015 review journal &lt;a href=&quot;https://doaj.org/article/602aea8253f84a068559bb763708c006?&quot;&gt;Ancient Egyptian Medicine: A Systematic Review&lt;/a&gt;. However, there were instances of “miracle” cures and medicine like Doan’s Backache Kidney Pills, as reported by previous student &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Esteve-Medicine/&quot;&gt;Justin Esteve&lt;/a&gt;. Nevertheless, the medicine used in Egypt was produced in different ways and counter products such as in mineral-based compounds, set milk, honey using tropical, oral methods, according to an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27594551&quot;&gt;Treatment Adherence and Beliefs about Medicines among Egyptian Vitiligo Patients&lt;/a&gt; published in Dermatologic Theraphy Journal in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/organic%20medicines/CastroLeyna-NaturesSkinFood/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Accidental Shooting</title>
				<link>/curiosities/Beasley-AccidentalShooting/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;On January 22nd, 1906 the Egyptian Gazette posted an article about an accidental shooting that occurred in the middle of page three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company by the name of Sudan Railways was the headline of Monday’s issue when it was heard that there was a shooting involving the company. A man named Mr. Sequino, a worker for Sudan Railways, was the main topic of this article. He had somehow managed to shoot himself in the mouth. Yes, in the mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owning a gun was unheard of in early twentieth century Egypt. Never the less owning a magnum, a powerful hand gun that packs a punch with a .45 caliber bullet. Working as a bridge foreman one day, Mr. Sequino ‘carelessly’ placed his gun down on a table and it managed to fall off. When reaching down to pick it up it fired a bullet straight at him, wedging the bullet through his two bottom front teeth, knocking them out, and sawing off part of his tongue. The event resulted in him having to take therapy lessons, basically learning how to speak again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guns typically don’t fire on their own, they need someone to pull the trigger. How Mr. Sequino’s gun fired on its own before he even contacted it is just absurd. It really leaves someone wondering about his personality, and if people in early twentieth century Egypt roamed the streets with unsafe handguns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, there are many articles within the Egyptian Gazette that give evidence that people owned and perhaps roamed the streets with guns and other types of weaponry. In my weekly issue there are instances where a rifle club appears, and there is an advertisement for the club practice. This means that people owned rifles in Egypt. Also, in an earlier week there is a mentioning about being able to trade in weapons for even better weapons that were once owned by criminals or murderers. These guns were taken away from them by the police, and then taken to a shop where citizens could trade or purchase them. Mr. Sequino might have purchased his revolver at a store like this, and as you can see, his purchase did not end in a good result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events like these are included all throughout the Egyptian Gazette. Page three is usually where useful and exciting information about royal families or the Khedive is placed in the newspaper. However, including comical and ridiculous stories such as the one with Mr. Sequino tells us that Egyptian journalism covered an array of topics. It also tells us that the community of Alexandria enjoyed keeping up with relevant and newly developing stories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/Beasley-AccidentalShooting/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Is Egypt In A Bubble?</title>
				<link>/curiosities/metallo-is-egypt-in-a-bubble/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Economies are cyclical. Fact. They will experience ups and downs. Fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the headlines of “Financial Crisis” glaring from the pages of the “Egyptian Gazette”, it is safe to assume that Egypt will be heading for an economical decline. As 1907 progresses, the financial situation in Egypt seems to be falling to great depths, and fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the May 5, 1907 edition of the “Egyptian Gazette” claims were made that the downturn was only impacting Cairo and Alexandria, it was “only confined to Alexandria and Cairo.” The positivity, as seen in the article below from May 1907, was meant to keep the entire country from panicking, preventing a self-fulfilling prophecy of a complete market collapse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/financial-positivity-19070521.JPG?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;financial positivity 19070521&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By June of 1907, only one month later, the country began to feel the effects of the crisis spreading further from the localized markets of Cairo and Alexandria. Banks began to suffer, stock prices began to drop, and the country was searching for an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image below is a screenshot from June 1907. It is now apparent that something needs to be done to solve the slipping economy.  The Alexandria Stock and Shareholders Association brought it upon themselves to attempt to curb the fall by creating a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?ei=6i7BWsOpLIX3zgLq6auwAQ&amp;amp;q=define+deputation&amp;amp;oq=define+deputation&amp;amp;gs_l=psy-ab.3..0j0i22i30k1l7.22758.23978.0.24069.10.8.0.0.0.0.226.613.0j1j2.3.0....0...1.1.64.psy-ab..7.3.611...35i39k1j0i10k1j0i22i10i30k1.0.SinQKTgLTj8&quot;&gt;deputation&lt;/a&gt; and appointing &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eldon_Gorst&quot;&gt;Sir Eldon Gorst&lt;/a&gt; as their deputy to lead them in their efforts.  Gorst was the controller of taxes and undersecretary of finances in Britain and was sent to Egypt to work along side Egyptian financial officials to fix their inevitable market meltdown.  He was also tasked with promoting native Egyptian responsibility in government positions (this did not happen and he would become hated by the old British rulers in Egypt and distrusted by Egyptain officials).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/sir-eldon-gorst.JPG?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;sir eldon gorst&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after, in the June 19, 1907 issue of the paper, the crisis was felt abroad, as seen in the article below from the introduction to a quote of a French article. Not only is the crisis officially “raging” in Egypt but is felt all over Europe (which, honestly, has the most to lose seeing as Egypt was still under European rule).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/blog-images/feeling-the-crisis-abroad-19070619.JPG?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;feeling the crisis abroad 19070619&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/metallo-is-egypt-in-a-bubble/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Advertising... Has anything really changed?</title>
				<link>/curiosities/majonica-advertisment-has-not-changed/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I happen to really enjoy encoding “The Egyptian Gazette.” It is almost therapeutic. As I venture into another day of my week in January of 1907, I have become accustomed with its format, easily pulling code from other parts of the paper I, and my classmates, have already worked on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of the paper is the advertisement section. No hassle of OCR, lots of pictures, and its sheer simplicity makes me feel like an encoding wiz. And when I was working on my Thursday issue, I imagined myself reading “The Egyptian Gazette” in Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was surprisingly simple for me, to read the newspaper as if I always had, as I even began to memorize the advertisements in the same way people living in Alexandria probably did, knowing their location and contents by heart. Interestingly enough, the most common advertisements seemed to be for travel, focused on both steamship movements and hotels. However, I did not really enjoy reading these advertisements, and even worse were the ones relating to finance or insurance. My favorite by far were the advertisements related to health. These advertisements were less common, but they were unique, scattered throughout the paper making me feel as if I was on a scavenger hunt in search of the next one. They are the complete opposite of the steamship and hotel advertisements that overwhelm the first, second, and last page of the paper. I actually wanted to read the health advertisements because who isn’t intrigued by the idea of something that can make one feel or look better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each and every time I see an advertisement for Peruna, a medicine advertised for women, the miracle stories about how it has changed people’s lives, as well its format and illustrations, catch my attention. Peruna’s advertisements jump off the page, unlike the steamer and hotel advertisements whose contents are seemingly stagnant and are not eye-catching at all. The Mena House Hotel advertisement is an example of their lackluster design, with its only description being that it is a “First Class Family Hotel.” Hard to say if I would stay there. The same goes for the boring advertisement for the Savoy Palace Hotel, which does not get me excited at all for it to open “shortly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How different are these advertisement tactics from that of today? Not very; the same tactics are used, especially when advertising medicine, as “success” stories continue to be attached to medicines sold in present day. Yet, in terms of travel, it is easier for hotels to excite the consumer today with vivid websites that show luxurious amenities at the click of a button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/the-evolution-of-cigarette-advertising/&quot;&gt;although their contents may have shifted&lt;/a&gt;, people are still consumed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/nunez-blogpost/&quot;&gt;products that provide personal benefit&lt;/a&gt;, and travel, because even now commercials, computer and phone advertisements everywhere consist of these things, similarly to that of Egypt in 1907. In Alexandria it seems that just like in 2018, trying to get the daily news comes with an unexpected bombardment of advertisements that we love to hate, but hate to love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to look more into advertising and its impact in present day with technology and print, check out these links below:
1. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/technology-is-radically-changing-the-advertising-business--and-the-consequences-are-profound-2014-9&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; talks about how advertising is changing to target the consumer, which is interesting because specific advertisements from “The Egyptian Gazette” were of interest to me, and are probably of interest to you, a concept this article explores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://businesstown.com/magazine-newspaper-direct-mail-advertising-still-work&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; focuses on the idea that print advertisement is in fact not dead, but actually extremely effective because our brains work in such a way that makes us better at memorizing print advertisements over digital ones. In terms of “The Egyptian Gazette” this article highlights the effectiveness of the advertisement section to those who read the newspaper in Alexandria and how it could have bolstered consumer activity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesagencycouncil/2017/08/15/10-years-on-the-iphones-impact-on-advertising/#355d49218fb7&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; analyzes the changes in advertising ten years after the release of the iPhone. When looking at the advertisements in “The Egyptian Gazette” in comparison to the advertisements that we interact with in the present day, this article dissects this transition from them to now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/majonica-advertisment-has-not-changed/</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Domestic Tragedy</title>
				<link>/curiosities/donofrio-tragedy/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This article tells the story of a divorced couple that ultimately ended in fatality. In attempts to fix his relationship, the spouse tried to convince his former wife to get back together. However, when she refused, he got angry and stabbed her multiple times. After this violent and impulsive reaction had subsided, the man realized what he had done, and thinking he had killed his spouse, he drew a revolver and shot himself dead. However, the woman simply fell unconscious and did not die.
This story has a theme similar to Shakespeare’s &lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt; pertaining to the story of a spouse thinking his partner is dead and consequentially killing himself because of that thought. It also shows that people would do anything for love, and that people act irrationally when they are put in desperate situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, domestic violence was not uncommon, as shown in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/cooper-wife-murder/&quot;&gt;Matthew Cooper’s blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Here Cooper talks about an article on a man who killed his wife with an blow to the head by a bar of iron. Although the context is different between the two instances, it is clear that abuse within marriages was not uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/curiosities/donofrio-tragedy/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
